（呉慶(ごけい)）父上！ 母上！
Father! Mother!
（呉慶）離せ！ 離せ！
Let me go! Let me go!
父上！ 母上！
Father! Mother!
父上… 母上…
Father... Mother...
It started with the slaughter at Wan Castle,
（麃公(ひょうこう)）丸城(がんじょう)の皆殺しから始まり
これまで 両軍 多くの血を流した
and now, much blood from both armies has spilled.
Wu Qing.
（麃公）
呉慶… ようやく会えたのぅ
We finally meet.
（王騎(おうき)）ンフフッ…
ハアッ！
ハアーッ！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
（信(しん)）ンンッ！
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Wise General VS Courageous General
ハアッ！
（麃公）オリャー！
What?! They came out even?!
（壁(へき)）なに？ 五分だと？
（信）将軍！
General!
麃公！
（麃公）呉慶！
Biao Gong!
Wu Qing!
（尾到(びとう)）すげえことになったぞ
（尾平(びへい)）頑張れ！ 麃公将軍！
Man, this is incredible.
Hang in there, General Biao Gong!
オリャー！
呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！
General Qu Qing! General Qu Qing! General Qu Qing!
General Qu Qing! General Qu Qing! General Qu Qing! General Qu Qing!
（兵士たち）
呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！
呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！
（兵士たち）
呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！
General Qu Qing! General Qu Qing!
（兵士たち）
呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！
呉慶将軍！ 呉慶将軍！
こ… これは…
（信）マズイんじゃねえのか？
Th-This is...
It's bad, ain't it?
（壁）これで魏(ぎ)の大将は力を増す
This will add to Wei's Great General's power.
追い詰められて
おかしくなったかと思ったが
I thought it was weird he got cornered like this.
自信があったのか
Was he that confident?
（信）この大声援の後押しも
初めから狙ってやがったな？
He was aiming to be pushed by these cheers from the beginning.
大将同士の一騎打ちだ
That it would be a one-on-one fight between generals.
２人の勝敗は
そのまま戦の勝敗になっちまうぞ
And the winner of the fight between the two would be the winner of the whole war!
おい！ こっちも声出して
将軍に檄(げき)を送ろうぜ！
Hey, let's get some cheers going, too!
We'll give some excitement to the general!
Unless we do something, he won't be able to use his full strength!
このままじゃ 将軍の力が出ねえ！
（武将）
そんなもの 将軍には必要ない
The general has no need for such a thing.
一騎打ちになった時点で
勝敗は決している
The moment it became a one-on-one battle, the winners and losers were decided.
えっ？ どういう意味だよ？
What do you mean?!
麃公さまと
一騎打ちで渡り合える者など
In all of China, the number of people who could be a match against Lord Biao Gong
中華全域でも
数えるほどしかおりはせぬ
could be counted on one's fingers.
Wu Qing's military strength will not possibly reach that of Lord Biao Gong's.
（武将）呉慶の武は
麃公さまには 到底 及ばぬ
（信）えっ… じゃ 将軍は今
手を抜いて 遊んでるってのか？
Then the general is holding back and just playing around right now?
（武将）そうではない　将軍は
呉慶を知ろうとしておられるのだ
He is not.
The general is getting to know Wu Qing.
（信）“知る”？
Getting to know?
不思議なお方なのだ 麃公さまは
He is a mysterious person indeed,
Lord Biao Gong.
But it is likely for him to soon make his move.
だが もうそろそろ動かれるぞ
Lord Biao Gong! Lord Biao Gong!
（じい）呉慶さま！
Lord Biao Gong!
ひと太刀目で
貴様の覚悟と気迫は伝わった
With the first strike of my sword, I could tell the level of your resolve and vigor.
But with my second, I lost track of the location of your soul.
じゃが ふた太刀目で
貴様の魂の居所を見失った
呉慶！ 貴様 一騎打ちに出たのは
武人の血が騒いだからではないな？
Wu Qing!
You did not enter a one-on-one fight in order to excite your warrior's blood, did you?!
どんな くだらぬ理由で
このわしに挑んできた？
For what pathetic reason did you challenge me?!
I would like to hear it before I kill you.
殺す前に聞いておいてやろうぞ
General!
将軍！
（呉慶）麃公…
Biao Gong. There dwells within me something far more heated than the blood of a warrior
武人の血などよりも
熱きものが我の中にあることを…
この剣をもって 教えてやろう
and with this sword, I will tell you what that is.
面白いのぅ
Interesting.
ソリャ！
（斬る音）
どうした？ 終わりか？
What's wrong? Are you finished?
Biao Gong...
麃公…
（兵士Ａ）呉慶さま
（呉慶）うん？
Lord Wu Qing!
（兵士Ａ）戦いをやめて
全軍に麃公を討てと号令ください
Please, stop fighting and order the whole army to attack Biao Gong.
秦国の兵士を皆殺しにし
自軍に箝口令(かんこうれい)を敷けば―
We'll slaughter all of the State of Qin's foot soldiers
and if you issue a gag order on your own army,
一騎打ち自体も
なかったことにできます
we can make it so the one-on-one battle itself never happened.
我らに任せて
どうか呉慶さまは お下がりを
Leave it to us.
I ask that you please hand down the duty to us.
（兵士Ｂ）呉慶さま 一体…
（兵士Ｃ）呉慶さま…
Lord Wu Qing! What in the world...?
Lord Wu Qing!
（呉慶）フフフッ… 侵略者に対し
ここまで ひくことができぬとは…
Up against invader, to not retreat at this point...
正直 自分でも驚きだ
人の感情とは ままならぬものだな
honestly surprises even myself.
People's emotions are beyond their control.
ほう… 冷徹な男かと思ったが
意外と情念が深いと見える
Oh? I thought you were a cool-headed man
but now I can see deep passion.
敵に侵略され
家族でも殺されたか！
Were you invaded by enemies,
and perhaps had your family killed?
家族だけではない
It was not just my family!
What was killed... was my country itself!
殺されたのは 国そのものだ！
“国を殺された”？
His country... was killed?
今から30年前
30 years ago, a small country called Jia, located in the east of Wei, was destroyed by Zhao.
魏の国の東にあった甲(こう)という小国が
趙(ちょう)に滅ぼされた
And I was part of that country's royal family!
我は その小国の王族だ
He's a survivor of the ruling family of a ruined country?
亡国の王室の生き残りか
（呉慶）名を変え 顔に墨を入れた
I changed my name and tattooed my face.
別人となり 放浪し 魏に流れ着いた
I became a different person, wandered, and eventually made my way to Wei.
そして 信陵君(しんりょうくん)の加護により
名を取り戻し
With the help of Lord Xinling, I regained my name
魏の国が 第２の祖国となった
and the State of Wei became my second fatherland.
だが あの日 見た
ごうごうと燃ゆる城の光景は―
But... The landscape I saw on that day of that rumbling, blazing castle...
片ときも忘れたことはない
I have not forgotten it, even an instant.
I see.
なるほどのぅ
So you were taken captive by that grudge,
では その私怨にとらわれ ノコノコ
このわしに挑んできたというわけか
and carelessly challenged me, is that it?
国を失うことが どういうことか
貴様に理解はできぬわ！
Do you know what it means to lose your country?
You could not possibly understand!
（麃公）くだらん負け犬の感傷だな
It's meaningless sentiment of a loser!
（麃公）
小国の淘汰は 戦国の世の常
It is normal in this world of warring states for small countries to be weeded out!
Your lick of distress is just one out of those many!
貴様のなめた苦汁など
そこら中に転がっておるわ
戦場にあって
身の上話など 何の意味も持たぬ
On the battlefield, stories of one's history have no meaning whatsoever!
For soldiers, all that matters is how to defeat the enemy in front of them.
兵ならば
“目の前の敵をどう倒すか”
将ならば“敵軍に どう勝つか”
それ以外に心とらわれることはない
For generals, all that matters is how to defeat the enemy general!
One's heart cannot be captive of anything else!
（麃公）将の責務よりも
私情を優先させた貴様に待つのは
To place your own feelings above your duty as general, you have become the picture of defeat!
“敗北”の２文字
来い 呉慶！ 秦国大将軍の
名において 引導を渡してやる！
Come, Wu Qing!
As a Great General of the State of Qin, I will put an end to you!
Has the air changed?
（呉慶）空気が変わったか
否 変えたのは麃公か
No. What's changed is Biao Gong.
燃ゆる城を見て 悟ったことがある
When I saw that castle burn, I understood something.
In this world, there is often something huge that most people do not understand in the justice they conceive of.
この世には およそ
人の考えうる正義が全く通じぬ―
強大なものがあるということ
今 我にとって それは麃公
And for me right now, that is Biao Gong.
If he hits, my body is sure to be destroyed.
当たらば 必ず こちらの身が滅ぶ
だが それでも…
But even so...
それでも…
Even so...
我は ひかぬ！
I will not retreat!
That ingenuity, that had you in a close fight with me up to this point,
ここまで わしを苦戦させた知略と
最後に 武に走ったその激情
and that passion you put in your fighting at the end...
なかなか
見事な大炎であったぞ 呉慶
made quite a great flame, Wu Qing!
Victory cry!
（武将）勝ち鬨(どき)じゃ！
As he heard the victory cry of the soldiers, Xin's eyes were captured not by the victorious General Biao Gong,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
兵士たちの勝ち鬨を聞きながら
そのとき 信は
勝利した麃公将軍ではなく―
but by the tragic sight of the collapsed General Wu Qing.
無残に倒れた呉慶将軍の姿に
目を奪われていた
死してもなお 呉慶の瞳には―
Because even dead, the eyes of Wu Qing
まだ小さな炎が
くすぶっていたからである
still had a small flame smoldering in them.
Seeing that sight made Xin mutter something in his mind.
そのサマに
信は 心の中でつぶやいた
"So this is a general?"
“これが将軍なのか”と
こうして 戦の趨勢(すうせい)は決した
And so, the flow of the war was decided.
麃公に付き従ってきた
秦国軍の兵士は3,000
3,000 Qin soldiers accompanied Biao Gong
それを囲む魏国の兵は
５万を超えていた
and over 50,000 Wei soldiers surrounded them.
だが 魏の軍の中に
落とした肩を上げる者は―
But there wasn't a single soldier among the Wei army that raised their fallen shoulders.
誰ひとりとして いなかった
（じい）呉慶さま…
Lord Wu Qing...
The mighty general known as Wu Qing
呉慶という名将の存在は―
魏の軍にあって
あまりに大きすぎたのである
was too great a presence for the Wei Army.
唯一 魏国軍の戦意を
取り戻す可能性を持つ副将―
In front of the one Vice General, that had any possibility of restoring the fighting spirit of the State of Wei Army, Bai Guixi,
白亀西(はくきさい)の前には
この男が立ちはだかった
stood that man.
（白亀西）貴様は…
You're...
久方ぶりに
いいものを見せていただきました
I was able to see something good for the first time in quite a while.
これ以上 戦いを長引かせても
蛇足以外の何ものでもないでしょう
To prolong this battle any further
would only be superfluous.
それとも
先ほどの一騎打ち以上のものを―
Or do you have the confidence that you can make something even greater than that one-on-one fight
この王騎と
繰り広げる自信がおありですか？
unfold with me, Wang Qi?
お… 王騎…
W-Wang Qi!
あっ！ おう 見ろ！
（尾平）あっ！
Look!
（尾平）魏の軍が ひいていく…
The Wei Army is... retreating.
アア…
（尾平）勝った？
We won...?
We... won...?
（尾平）勝った… 俺たちが？
We won!!
俺たちが勝ったんだ！
（歓声）
（尾平）ウウ…
（尾到）あ… 兄貴…
Big Brother!
（尾平）生き残った…
生き残ったぞ バカ野郎
We survived... We survived, you damn idiot...
Even though so many people died...
大勢 死んだのに…
（泣き声）
第４軍の歩兵も
ほかの軍のヤツらも…
from the 4th Army and all the other armies...
縛虎申(ばくこしん)千人将も…
and even Thousand Man General Fu Hushen!
ちきしょう！ ちきしょう！
（地面を殴る音）
Dammit! Dammit!
We won, goddammit!
勝ったぞ！ ちきしょう！
（王騎）ンフッ…
随分とお久しぶりです 麃公将軍
It has been quite a while, General Biao Gong.
（麃公）おお 王騎か！
Oh, Wang Qi?
貴様が丘の上から
にらみを利かせたおかげで―
You holding authority from atop that hill
だいぶ助けられたわ フフッ…
（王騎）いえいえ
gave us quite a bit of help.
Oh, no. I was merely passing by, doing some sightseeing.
私は ただ通りかかって
見物させていただいただけですよ
ところで 将軍
ここから どうするつもりですか？
By the way, General, what do you plan to do from here?
このまま
攻めに出るおつもりですか？
Will you continue on to an attack?
それとも…
Or else...
うむ…
Once a great flame is calmed, immediately reigniting it is next to impossible.
一度 昇華した大炎
すぐさま おこすは 至難この上なし
To all units,
全軍に告ぐ！
帰国じゃ！
we're returning home!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）始皇(しこう)２年 紀元前245年
In Shi Huang Year 2, 245 BCE,
秦国と魏国との間に
起きた ひとつの戦は 終結を見た
there was a gathering of troops for one battle between the State of Qin and the State of Wei.
だが…
But...
天下の大将軍を目指す信にとって
For Xin, who aimed to become the greatest general under the heavens,
それは まだ
小さな始まりにすぎなかった
that was nothing more than a small beginning.
In a world where seven kingdoms battled in violent wars,
７つの国が
激しく争う戦乱の世において
戦いの火種は
また いくつも生まれていた
many sparks of war were still coming into being.
General, huh...?
将軍か… なるぞ 俺も
I'm gonna be one, too.
State of Qin   Anjian
（貂(てん)）
どうして こんなに死体ばっかり…
Why are there so many corpses here...?
（貂）
戦に勝ったんじゃなかったのかよ？
We won the war, didn't we?
（兵士）いてっ！
Ow!
Y-You're alive!
ウワッ！ い… 生きてる！
（兵士）生きてるよ
Yeah, I am.
なんで
死んだマネなんかしてるんだよ！
Why're you pretending you're dead like that?!
するか そんなもん！ 命からがら
ここまで引き揚げてきて―
I am not!
I barely made it out with my life and was brought here with the salvaged corpses.
Everyone had collapsed.
みんな ぶっ倒れたんだ
（貂）“命からがら”って…
勝ったんだろう？
Barely made it with your life? You won, didn't you?
ああ… だが
こっちも たくさん やられたんだ
Yeah. But we had a lotta losses, too.
こっから出兵した第４軍なんか
ほとんど全滅なんだよ
And the 4th Army that got dispatched from here almost got completely wiped out!
Wiped out?
全滅？
（信）おう！ なんだ お前
こんな所まで来てたのか
What's with you?
Why'd ya come to a place like this?
なっ？ 妙な格好してるだろう
（尾平）うん 確かに
So? He's got weird clothes, doesn't he?
Heh. Ya got a point.
うん？ どうした？
What's up?
Don't give me that "What's up?", you idiot!
“どうした”じゃねえだろう！
このバカ！
アア… 麻鬼(まき)にやられた傷が…
（尾平）大丈夫か？ 信
The wound I got from Ma Gui!
Are you okay, Xin?
痛(いて)えな こら！
（貂）うるせえ！
That hurt, dammit!
Shut up!
大体 手柄
ちゃんと上げてきたんだろうな？
Anyhow, you got some achievements, right?!
ヘッ… ばっちしよ！
Sure did.
よ～し！ お疲れ！
（信）あっ うん…
Okay! Good job!
3 Months Later
（露天商）
さあ いらっしゃいませ
（露天商）毎度！
（露天商）おいしいよ！
（露天商）さあさあ おにいさん！
（貂）わあ～！ ここ すげえな！
This place sure is amazing.
うまそうな食い物
いっぱい売ってる
They're selling tons of delicious looking foods...
なあ 信！
（信）そう急ぐなよ
Don'cha think, Xin?
Don't be in such a rush.
（貂）あっ 信！ あの店！
うまそうな食い物 売ってんぞ
Xin! That shop!
They're selling some really tasty lookin' stuff!
食い物(もん)なんか後回しだ
We'll get food later.
（貂）
えっ？ お前 どっか具合悪いの？
Are you not feeling well?
I told you, didn't I?
だから 言っただろう　今日は―
We're using this reward money I saved up to buy some armor.
この たんまりいただいた褒賞金で
甲冑(かっちゅう)を買うんだよ
（貂）へえ！ 食い物より先に
考えることがあるなんて―
Heh. You're thinking about something before food?
立派になったもんだ　さすがは…
You sure have grown up.
Just what I'd expect from a Hundred...
うん… 甲冑は あとのお楽しみだ
先に 腹ごしらえにしとくか
We'll enjoy that armor later on.
How about we fill our stomachs right now?
（店主）いらっしゃい！
オッ… 見ない顔だな
Welcome!
Oh, here are some faces I haven't seen before.
３つも向こうの村から
はるばる来たんだ
We came all the way from three villages over.
こいつが“甲冑買う”とか言って
This guy was talking about buying armor.
Armor? You, sir?
甲冑？ お前さんが？
初陣から甲冑着てくのか？
Are you here to get armor for your first campaign?
My first campaign is over.
初陣は終わった
この前の戦で もらった金で
甲冑買うんだよ
I'm buying the armor with money I earned in the last war.
はぁ？ この前の戦っていやぁ
三月(みつき)前に魏の国とやり合ったやつだ
The last war?
You mean the one three months ago against the State of Wei?
All the people from around here were in the 4th Army
この辺りから行った者(もん)は
第４軍に入って―
ほとんどが死んだんだぞ
つまんねえウソを…
and most of them died.
What a dull lie.
だから その第４軍で活躍して―
I'm tellin' you!
I was in that 4th Army and got money from it, dammit!
金もらったんだよ 俺は！
（店主）ごめんなさい
I-I'm sorry!
（田有(でんゆう)）おお 今日は騒がしいな
Sure is busy today.
あれ？ こいつ…
Huh? This guy...
Oh, some real heroes from the 4th Army have come.
ほら！
本物の第４軍の英雄が来られたぞ
If it isn't the mounted soldier!
（田有）おお！ これは 騎兵どの！
（信）伍(ご)を作るときに
１番人気だったおっさん！
You're the old man who was the most popular when we were making Wus!
Looks like you're doing well, mounted soldier.
元気そうだな 騎兵どの
（信）“信”でいいよ
おっさんも元気そうだな
Just call me Xin.
You look okay yourself, old man.
（子分）棟梁(とうりょう) このガキ…
いや 少年が ホントに例の？
Boss, is this brat...
I mean this boy really that one?
Yeah. This boy...
ああ　この少年こそ―
先の魏との戦で 奮迅の活躍をして
歩兵から 一気に…
In that war with Wei, he put on an incredible performance and went right from foot soldier all the way to...
百人将の位に駆け上がった信だ！
Xin rose to the rank of Hundred Man General!
（町人Ａ）百人将っていやぁ
100人の部隊の隊長だぞ
Hundred Man General?
That means he's a captain of a unit of one hundred people!
In just one war?
（町人Ｂ）たった１度の戦で？
こんな子供が？
A kid like this?
It's an exception among exceptions, but I truly think it was the right decision.
（田有）異例中の異例だが
極めて正当な評価だ
If it weren't for Xin, forget the 4th Army,
信がいなければ
第４軍はおろか―
あの戦自体
どうなっていたか分からん
I don't know what would've happened with that whole war.
Aw, you're exaggerating.
大げさだよ
戦からの帰り
みんなが信のことを語っていた
On the way back from the war, everyone was talking about Xin.
しばらくして
百人将になったと聞いて
When I'd heard he was being made a Hundred Man General,
我がことのように うれしかったぜ
（信）そ… そうか？
I was as happy as if it were me being made one.
R-Really?
こんなに次の戦が待ち遠しいのは
初めてだ
It's the first time I've been looking forward to the next war this much.
お前の部隊で
戦ってみてえと思ってるヤツは―
And I'll bet you I'm not the only one who'd like to fight in your unit.
きっと俺だけじゃないぜ
俺の隊は とんでもなく大変だぜ
ヘヘッ…
My unit's gonna be really something.
You must be glad, Xin.
良かったな 信　甲冑買えて
You were able to buy armor.
ヘヘヘッ… かっけえだろう
（貂）うん…
Looks good, doesn' it?
No it doesn't.
そんなことない
自慢すんな ガキか
Don't act so proud. Are you a little kid?
えっ？ どっちだよ？
（貂）だから それは…
About what?
Anyhow, uh...
信 お前 またでかくなった…
You got bigger again.
お前は… 羌瘣(きょうかい)！
You...
Qiang Lei!
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
I have only one reason for living.
（羌瘣）私が生きている理由は
ひとつしかない
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秘められた過去
２人きりの夜に 魂が震える
A hidden past.
In a night where two people are all alone,
souls shake.
Night Tale
End
Next time.
次回 “夜語り”